(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
猫又おかゆ 分かり手グランプリ！
Nekomata Okayu's "Who Knows Her Best?" Grand Prix!
はい、ということで皆さん、ついにこの日がやってきました。
Alright, everyone, the day has finally come.
猫又おかゆによる、猫又好きが参加する、猫又おかゆのための企画です。
A project by Nekomata, for Nekomata lovers, dedicated to Nekomata Okayu.
皆さん猫又好きですよね？
You all love Nekomata, right?
好き好き！大好き！
Yes! We love her!
ありがとうございます。まずは今宵のチャレンジャーの皆さんを紹介しましょう。
Thank you. First, let me introduce tonight's challengers.
ではまず、大空スバルさん！
First up, Oozora Subaru!
はい！ちわーす！
Yes! Hello!
なんか気がついたら猫又好きに呼ばれていました。イキリアヒル、大空スバルです！
Before I knew it, I was called here as a Nekomata lover. Cocky Duck, Oozora Subaru!
今日はどんな人が来ようとも、全員ボコボコにして1位の座を獲得していきたいと思います。
I'm going to beat everyone here and take the number one spot.
よろしくお願いしまーす！
Nice to meet you all!
では次、ミオちゃん！
Next, Mio-chan!
はい！うち、うち、うちだよ！大神ミオだよ！
Yes! It's me, me, me! Ookami Mio!
まあね、猫又好きとして参戦させていただきましたが、
Well, I'm here as a Nekomata lover,
まあ、うちはおかゆのことよく分かってるというか、まあ、気が合うことが多いから。
and I understand Okayu very well, or rather, we click on many things.
おかゆの気持ちはよく分かってるんじゃないかなって。優勝しちゃうかもな。
I think I understand how she feels perfectly. I might just win this.
隣で勝ち切れてる人が……。
The person next to her looks so confident...
あれ、勝ち切れてる？
Wait, are they?
じゃあ、ちょっとよく見たら頭に青筋が浮いている、ころさーん。
Then, looking closely, there's a vein popping on her head, Koro-san.
何？青筋？これ？これ？
What? A vein? This? This?
大丈夫だよ。今夜はおかゆのこと知ってますから。
It's fine. I know all about Okayu tonight.
本人より詳しいと思うから、本人より。あげ。よろしくね。
I think I know her better than she knows herself. Age. Nice to meet you.
何ですかそれ。初めて聞きましたね。
What's that? Never heard that one before.
では本日、皆さんには世界中の猫又おかゆ好きを代表して、
Today, representing all Nekomata Okayu lovers worldwide,
様々な猫又おかゆクイズに挑戦してもらいます。
you'll be challenged with various Nekomata Okayu quizzes.
そうですよ、世界代表ですよ、皆さんは。
That's right, you are the world representatives.
おー！やったー！
Oh! Yay!
名誉なことです。
It's an honor.
ちょっと雑じゃね！？
That was a bit casual, wasn't it?!
ちょっと久しぶりのね、SMOKということで。
It's been a while since we had the SMOK crew together.
猫又おかゆを愛してやまない皆さんなら、当然、正解できますよね？
As people who love Okayu to death, you'll obviously get the answers right, correct?
はい！もちろん！
Yes! Of course!
では早速参りましょう！
Then let's get right into it!
早速！？もう！？
Already?! Right now?!
参っていきます。お、ビビってんのか？帰ってもいいんだぞ。
We're going. Oh, are you scared? You can go home if you want.
帰らない！帰らない！一番帰っちゃダメな人だよ！
We're not going home! You're the one who shouldn't be saying that!
書いたらだめだ。
You shouldn't write that yet.
暫定一位はやめてくださいね。
Please stop with the "provisional first place".
暫定一位！
Provisional first place!
はい、ではやっていきましょう！
Alright, let's get started!
はーい！
Okay!
では、一問目お願いします！
Now, for the first question!
はい、問題！
Okay, the question!
猫又おかゆを漢字で表すなら？
If you were to represent Nekomata Okayu with a Kanji?
「猫」以外でお答えください。
Please answer with something other than "Cat".
え、なになに？なぞなぞ？
Eh, what, what? A riddle?
「猫」以外？余裕！
Other than "Cat"? Easy!
なぞなぞではないよ。
It's not a riddle.
なぞなぞではない？
Not a riddle?
え、「猫」以外でか...
Eh, besides "Cat"...
え、これしかも、自分が...
Eh, and this is like, something you...
うん、これ答えてるんでしょ？
Yeah, you've already answered this, right?
あれ、これはおかゆが答えた答えを当てるってことでしょ？
Wait, this is about guessing the answer Okayu gave?
そう、僕が答えた答え。
Yes, the answer I gave.
だから僕がなんて書くかなーっていうのを想像して書いてください。
So, imagine what I would write and write it down.
簡単だよ！
It's easy!
お、ミオちゃんはなんか書いてますね。
Oh, Mio-chan is writing something.
なんかこれ、これしかないですよ、やっぱりおかゆといえば。
This, there's only this, after all, when it comes to Okayu.
おかゆといえばこれ！ってことだ。じゃあ。
"When you think of Okayu, it's this!" That's it.
これじゃない？
Isn't it this?
あ、あ、なるほど！なるほどなるほど！
Ah, I see! I see, I see!
ミオちゃんと、ころさんは書きそろってますね。
Mio-chan and Koro-san have finished writing.
ズバババ書いた。
Wrote it real fast.
何笑ってんねん。
What are you laughing at?
何笑ってんねん。え、違うの？待って。
What are you laughing at? Eh, is it different? Wait.
いやいや、なんか可愛いなと思って。
No, no, I just thought it was cute.
オプション付いてたからさ。
Because it had an option attached.
あ、皆さん書き終えました？
Ah, has everyone finished writing?
はい、書いた。
Yes, finished.
書き終わった人？
Who's finished?
はい！はーい！はい！
Me! Me! Yes!
では出そろったということで、回答お願いします！
Well, now that everyone's ready, answers please!
あ、ではスバルちゃんいいですか？
Ah, well then, Subaru-chan, are you ready?
発表お願いします！オープン！
Please announce it! Open!
オープン！
Open!
夜！
Night!
これですね！
This is the one!
おかゆといえば夜型。
When you think of Okayu, she's a night owl.
おかゆはデビュー当時、夜の...何だっけ？
When Okayu debuted, she was the... what was it?
夜の帝王。
Emperor of the Night.
帝王！名乗ってた。
Emperor! You were calling yourself that.
確かに言ってた！
You definitely were!
夜だ！
It's Night!
ということで、スバルちゃんは「夜」という回答でした。
So, Subaru-chan's answer was "Night".
では次、ミオちゃんの回答を見ていきましょう。
Now next, let's see Mio-chan's answer.
では、ミオちゃん、オープン！
Now, Mio-chan, open!
罪！
Sin!
うわー、その可能性ある！
Whoa, that's a possibility!
罪です！
It's Sin!
いや、しかもね、猫又おかゆ裁判の主犯じゃないですけど。
Well, and also, I'm not the ringleader of the Nekomata Okayu Trial, but...
主催はミオちゃんでしたからね、当時。
Mio-chan was the organizer back then.
確かに、血の涙を猫が流してる。
Indeed, the cat is shedding tears of blood.
裁判官としてね。
As a judge.
罪もあるし、罪深くもあるんだけど、
There's sin, and she is sinful,
なんかこう、人たらしなところも罪だ、みたいな。
Like, how she's a lady-killer is also a sin.
罪にしてみました。
I went with Sin.
捨てました！おばち、どうぞ。
Thrown away! Obachi, go ahead.
では最後、ころさんお願いします！
Now finally, Koro-san, please!
オープン！
Open!
お、何これ？
Oh, what's this?
何か、女？
Something, woman?
ちょっとおどろおどろしいビール。
A slightly eerie beer?
まつ毛が入ってない。
The eyelashes aren't there.
あ、本当だ。そういう意味じゃない、そこじゃない多分。
Ah, you're right. That's not what she means, not that part probably.
なんかこうボーイッシュな感じだけれども、
Has a tomboyish feel to her,
溢れ出る女が、最近隠し切れてないんじゃないかな。
Her overflowing womanhood hasn't been hidden lately, I think.
え、何それ。
Eh, what's that?
メス味のことだろそれ。
You mean a feminine aspect, don't you?
最近はね、これかなって思った。
Recently, I thought it might be this.
ずっと一緒にいるころさんにメスのこと指摘されると、なんか一番恥ずかしい。
Being pointed out about my femininity by Koro-san, who I'm always with, is kind of the most embarrassing.
でも可愛いぜ。
But it's cute.
ありがとう。
Thanks.
何見せられてんだ。
What are we being shown?
早く答えろ！
Hurry up and answer!
二十分またなきゃいけないのおかゆ。
We have to wait 20 minutes for Okayu.
そういうことで、では皆さんの回答出そろったところで、
So, with everyone's answers out,
僕の回答発表したいと思います！
I'd like to announce my answer!
では、僕の回答、ドキュン！
Now, my answer, bang!
馴染。
Blend in.
馴染む。
To blend in.
なじ、かっこつけちゃってお前は！
"Naji", you're just trying to look cool!
いや、まあ理由としては、結構その新しい新居に付いたりとかしても、
Well, the reason is, even when I move into a new place,
すぐなんかもう一年分前から自分の家に住んでるみたいだなって気持ちになるから。
I immediately feel like I've been living in my own home for a year.
馴染む。
Blend in.
という漢字なんですけど。
That's the Kanji.
コンビの反応見てよ。
Look at your duo's reaction.
え、こん、こんな漢字知らんし、まず。
Eh, I, I don't even know this Kanji, first of all.
漢字のレパートリー少ないんだからさ。
My Kanji repertoire is limited.
ちょっと難しい感じだったね。
It was a bit of a difficult one.
でもおかゆは知性高めだからな。
But Okayu has high intelligence.
どれだってこれで合ってるじゃん。
No matter which one, this is right.
見て。答え合ってるよ。
Look. The answer is right.
なんかさ、むしゃむしゃと…ぐにゃぐにゃの毛みたいなの乗ってるけど、大丈夫？
There's like... messy, wiggly hair on it. Is that okay?
不正だよ不正！
It's cheating! Cheating!
不正を働く、こんなだんだんに働くやついいの、不正？
Cheating... is it okay for someone to cheat like this on such a stage?
そうだよね。
That's right.
ありゃ、見られてただな。
Oh, I was seen.
ということでね皆さん、全員不正解ということで。全然わかり手じゃないよ！
So everyone, you were all incorrect. You're not "understanding ones" at all!
難しいな、なかなか。
That was quite difficult.
じゃ、次の問題行ってみましょうかね。それでは、次の問題お願いします！
Well, let's move on to the next question. Next question, please!
問題 猫又おかゆの座右の銘は？
Question: What is Nekomata Okayu's motto?
はい！猫又おかゆの座右の銘は？
Yes! What is Nekomata Okayu's motto?
えー！座右の銘？！
What?! A motto?!
それこそさっき…あれ？どうかな、どうかな？
Speaking of which, just now... Huh? I wonder, I wonder?
座右の銘、超難しいじゃん！うわ、でもなんか言ってた気がする。でもなんだったっけな…
A motto is super hard! Oh, but I feel like you've said it. But what was it...?
言ってた、言ってたぞ！いいと、いいと！いやでももう何も思い出せないけど。
She said it, she said it! Let's see... No, but I can't remember anything now.
なんかそれっぽいこと言ってた気がするホント。結局何も思い出してないじゃん、それは。
I really feel like I said something like that. In the end, you haven't remembered anything.
それっぽいこと今言っただけで何も思い出してないからね、ホントだよ！なんだろう？
I just said something like that and haven't remembered a thing, it's true! I wonder what it is?
座右の銘ってなに？
What is a motto?
座右の銘、例えば生きてきて、こういう言葉を胸に刻みたいな…という話ですよ。
A motto is, for example, a word you want to keep in your heart as you live... that's the kind of thing it is.
この言葉を…え…？
This word... uh...?
ま、思い浮かばなかったらさ、ころねさんが自分の好きな言葉が僕の好きな言葉かもしれないじゃん。
Well, if you can't think of anything, Korone-san, the word you like might be the word I like.
みおちゃんどうだい？うわお、難しいな。まず座右の銘自体がもう頭真っ白で何も思いつかないんだよね。
Mio-chan, how about you? Wow, it's hard. First of all, my mind is blank about the motto itself and I can't think of anything.
これだ！もう一発百中や！
This is it! A hundred shots, a hundred hits!
これだ！お、スバルちゃん書き終わってますね。
This is it! Oh, Subaru-chan has finished writing.
これです！自信ある？
It's this! Are you confident?
自信ありだそうです！マジすか。
She seems confident! Really?
さ、二人はどうでしょうか？今から書くよ。
Now, how about the other two? I'm going to write now.
お、なんか書き始めてる。お？なんか全部ひらがなで書いてる。
Oh, they're starting to write. Oh? She's writing everything in hiragana.
あ、なるほどね。はいはいはい。だいぶ出揃ってきましたよ。
Ah, I see. Right, right. We're almost all set.
スバルちゃんとみおちゃんは書き終わってますね。そうだね。
Subaru-chan and Mio-chan have finished writing. That's right.
な、なにこれ？！おけいよ。
W-what is this?! It's okay.
めちゃ長いんだけどめちゃ長いんだけど！
It's super long, it's super long!
ちらっと見えた画面。黒すぎて今。もっと座右の銘ってさ、そんな長いもんだけっけ？
I caught a glimpse of the screen. It's too black right now. Wait, are mottos usually that long?
知らないよ！ちょっと待って。ひらがな。書けた。
I don't know! Wait a minute. Hiragana. I wrote it.
えわ、そろそろね皆さんの書いてる解答を見ていきたいと思います。はい。では今回もスバルちゃんからどうぞ！
Well, it's about time to see the answers you've written. Yes. So, this time too, start with Subaru-chan!
沈黙は金 雄弁は銀！
Silence is golden, eloquence is silver!
沈黙は金 雄弁は銀
Silence is golden, eloquence is silver
あ、なるほどなるほど。これですね。あの、よく言ってますおかゆが実際。
Ah, I see, I see. It's this one. Well, Okayu actually says this often.
めちゃめちゃこう通話とかしてても、「いややっぱりねスバルちゃん、沈黙は金、雄弁は銀なんだよね」。
Even when we're on the phone, she's like, "Yeah, you know Subaru-chan, silence is golden, eloquence is silver."
え、待っておかゆ言ってくれたことないよ、そんなこと！ホントにそんなこと言われたことないよ！
Wait, Okayu has never said that to me! I've really never been told that!
え、どちらかというとスバルちゃんが「やっぱさ、雄弁は銀なんだよね」って言って「そうだよ、沈黙は金だね」っていういつものサポートじゃん。
Wait, isn't it more like Subaru-chan says "Eloquence is silver, right?" and then I give my usual support by saying "That's right, silence is golden."
スバルのサポートじゃん、それは！捏造だったかも。
That's just supporting Subaru! It might have been a fabrication.
いいえ、そうよね。どちらかというとスバルちゃんの座右の銘な気がするけどね。
No, that's right. I feel like that's more likely to be Subaru-chan's motto.
じゃ、それも間違いってことじゃん。ま、でもね、これかもしれないからね。
Then that means it's wrong too. Well, but it might be this.
では、みおちゃんの解答を見てみましょう。こちらです。
Now, let's see Mio-chan's answer. Here it is.
明日は我が身！これこそスバルちゃんの座右の銘じゃない？
Tomorrow it could be me! Isn't this one definitely Subaru-chan's motto?
明日は我が身
Tomorrow it could be me
マジ？なんでそんなスバルちゃんの…あれ？めちゃ言う？明日は我が身って。
Really? Why so much about Subaru-chan... Huh? Do I say it often? "Tomorrow it could be me."
わかりみ選手権じゃないんですからね。 demo、かもしれない。
This isn't the "understanding ones" championship after all. But it might be.
これよくあれ？スバルちゃんが言ってるやつ？あれ？明日は我が身って。
Wait, is this something Subaru-chan often says? Huh? "Tomorrow it could be me."
よく言ってる？明日は我が身って。言ってる言ってる、ねこれ。どの時に言ってるんだっけ？
Does she say it often? "Tomorrow it could be me." She says it, she says it, right? When does she say it?
いや、「明日は我が身だよな」って言ってる。
No, I do say "Tomorrow it could be me."
確かに、ことあるたびにね。めちゃ言う。言ってる言ってる。までもおかゆが言ってるかもね。
Certainly, every chance she gets. She says it a lot. Well, but Okayu might be saying it too.
ころねさんの解答期待してみましょう。では、どん！なに？
Let's look forward to Korone-san's answer. Now, boom! What?
かなしいこともいっぱいあるけど、それはぜんぶこのさきのしあわせのためなんだ。だからだいじょうぶ！
There are many sad things, but they are all for the sake of future happiness. So it's okay!
わかるでしょ、これ。
You get this, right?
「塞翁の目」？新種じゃん。
'Saiou's Eye'? That's a new one.
これ、「塞翁の目」じゃないの？
Is this not 'Saiou's Eye'?
「ポエム」じゃん。「ポエム」だね。
It's a poem. It's a poem, right?
何文字...何文字までを
How many characters... how many characters
「塞翁の目」にしていいわけ？
are allowed to be 'Saiou's Eye'?
いや、でも、「なになになになに」くらいじゃない？
No, but, isn't it like 'blah blah blah blah'?
「なになになになに」。
'Blah blah blah blah.'
まあ、なんか有名な人が放った言葉、みたいな感じ。
Well, it's like a quote from a famous person.
それ、誰が放った言葉なの？
Who's the one who said that quote?
お、オリジン？起源ってこと？
O-origin? As in the origin?
ほら、ほら、なんかよく言うじゃん。
Look, look, it's a common saying.
オリジンなの？ちょっと「みつを」っぽいけどね。
Is it the origin? It looks a bit like 'Mitsuo' though.
ほら！みつをかもしれない。みつをだわ、それは。
See! It might be Mitsuo. It's Mitsuo, then.
みつをだろ、それは。みつをさんだ。
It's definitely Mitsuo. Mr. Mitsuo.
最後にビックリマークつけねえだろ、みつをさんは。
Mr. Mitsuo wouldn't put an exclamation mark at the end.
ではね、正解の方、行きましょうかね。
Well then, let's go to the correct answer.
この中に正解してる人はいるのか？
Is there anyone among you who got it right?
では、正解お願いします！
The correct answer, please!
せーの、ドン！
Ready, go!
あれ？出てこないな。
Huh? It's not coming up.
ドン！
Go!
あれ？あれ？なかなか来ないみたいですね、これ。
Huh? Huh? It's taking quite a while, isn't it?
あ、出てきた！
Ah, there it is!
はい、「塞翁が馬」です！
Yes, it's 'The Horse of Saiou'!
どういう意味ですか？
What does it mean?
聞いたことないです！
I've never heard of it!
あ、これは、例えば、
Ah, this is, for example,
いい自転車が半額で買えたと。
you were able to buy a good bicycle at half price.
で、その自転車に乗ってたら、
And, while you were riding that bicycle,
ま、転んじゃったと。
well, you fell off.
でも、転んだことによって得られたいいこともあるっていう、
But, there are also good things gained by falling,
その、いいことなんだけど、一概にいいこととも言えないし、
so, it's a good thing, but you can't say it's unconditionally good,
悪いこととも言えないね、っていう、
and you can't say it's bad either, is the...
そういうやつです。
kind of thing it is.
さっきからちょっと内容が難しすぎる気がします！
I feel like the content has been a bit too difficult for a while now!
IQが釣り合ってません！
Our IQs are not matching!
いやいや、そんなことないよ。
No, no, that's not true.
こら、転んじゃって全部ひらがなで書いてるじゃねえか！
Hey, you wrote the whole 'fell off' part in Hiragana, didn't you!
全部じゃない、全部じゃない。
Not all of it, not all of it.
全部ひらがなじゃねえか！
It's all Hiragana, isn't it!
いや、「大丈夫」とかは漢字で書いた。
No, I wrote 'Daijoubu' (It's okay) and stuff in Kanji.
なんだよ、書いたとかじゃねえよ！
What do you mean, 'I wrote it'!
じゃ、仮にみんなの、その、なに、感覚に下げたとしても、
Well, even if I were to lower it to your, you know, level of understanding,
ま、「焼肉定食」とかになっちゃうんじゃない？入るとしとも。
well, it would probably end up being something like 'Yakiniku Set Menu,' even if it were to fit.
ば、バカにされてる、うちら！
W-we're being made fun of!
あれ？我々、バカにされてます？
Huh? Are we being mocked?
はい、じゃあ、次の問題行きまーす！
Okay then, moving on to the next question!
次の問題、どうぞ！
Next question, please!
はい、猫又おかゆの「デビューしてから一番嬉しかった出来事」は？
Yes, what is Nekomata Okayu's 'happiest event since her debut'?
デビューしてから一番嬉しかったでしょ？
Happiest thing since debut, right?
デビューしてから一番嬉しかったこと。
Happiest thing since debut.
これはー...えー、聞いていい、ちょっと？
This is... er, can I ask you something?
ヒント欲しいね、ヒントが欲しいです。
I want a hint, I want a hint.
ちょっと待って、僕、なんて答え、書いたか忘れちゃった。
Wait a second, I forgot what answer I wrote.
嘘だろお前！
You've got to be kidding!
そんな嬉しくなかったんじゃねえの？
Maybe it wasn't that happy?
一番嬉しかった...あ、なんか書いて、あ、分かりました。
The happiest... ah, I wrote something, ah, I got it.
カンニングすんじゃねえ！
Don't cheat!
まあ、別にふざけたことは書いてないですねって感じ。
Well, it's not like I wrote anything silly.
うん。あ、別に分かった。
Yeah. Oh, I get it now.
真面目に書いてますね。
You're writing it seriously.
どうし、別に難しいことは書いてない。
Why, I'm not writing anything difficult.
デビューしてから一番嬉しかった出来事。
The happiest event since debut.
じゃあ、何かが起こったんだ。
So, something happened.
何でしょうね？
What could it be?
起こったの？起こったの？
Did it happen? Did it happen?
起こった。
It happened.
何か出来事か。
Some kind of event.
うん、あったあった。まあ、起こった。
Yeah, there was one. Well, it happened.
あ、あった。あ、分かったってよ。
Ah, there was. Oh, she says she got it.
じゃあ、スバルも分かった。
Then Subaru gets it too.
そろそろ正解してほしいよな。
I'd like you guys to get a correct answer soon.
そろそろ正解したいな。
I want to get one right soon.
わかりての、みんなとしては、そろそろ正解してほしいところですけどね。
As the Okayu-understanders, I'd like you guys to get one right soon.
これ、全問正解してる人いるんかな、今、リスナーさんとかで。
I wonder if anyone among the listeners has gotten all the questions right so far.
いないよ、どうだろね。僕だけかもしんない。
Probably not. I might be the only one.
ちょっと「わかりて選手権」の3人だから。
Because you're the three in the 'Okayu-understander Championship.'
まあね。
Well, yeah.
どうかな、どうかな。
How about it, how about it.
あ、ミオさんのやつも確かに、そうだよね。
Ah, Mio's is definitely like that, isn't it.
じゃあ、違うじゃん。
Then it's different.
いいね、なんか文字2色でグラデーションしてていいね。
Nice, I like how the characters have a two-color gradient.
そういう褒められ方したわけじゃないんだけど。
That's not exactly the kind of compliment I was looking for.
ころさんもカラフルでいいね。
Koro-san's is colorful too, nice.
お、なるほど。
Oh, I see.
スバルちゃん、結構オプション付きがちやね、文字の外に。
Subaru-chan, you tend to add a lot of options around the characters.
ね、いい、あれやん、先生やん。
Yeah, nice, you're like a teacher.
先生、これは。
Teacher, this is...
確かに、イラストがあると分かりやすくていいね。
True, it's nice having illustrations to make it easier to understand.
皆さん、どうですか？書き終わりました？
How is everyone doing? Finished writing?
では、誰から行こうかな。
Then, who should I start with?
じゃあ、ころさんから行こうか、次は。
Well then, let's start with Koro-san next.
了解！
Got it!
問題
猫又おかゆの「デビューしてから1番嬉しかった出来事」は？
Question:
What was Nekomata Okayu's "happiest moment since her debut"?
回答をオープンしたいと思います！
I'd like to open the answers!
では、ころさん、オープン！
Now, Koro-san, open!
素敵な友達ができた
I made wonderful friends
おおー！いいことだ、それは。
Oh! That's a good thing, that.
せっかくカラフルだったのに黒の字で…
Even though I made it colorful,
it's written in black...
あれだよね、カラーでグラデーションかけて
影みたいにしてるってことでしょ？
It's that, right? You used colors for a
gradient and made it look like a shadow, right?
だよね！
Right!
なんかすごい分かり合ってる、ここ二人が。
You two seem to understand each other really well.
にしても「できた」だけ真っ黒やないかい。
Even so, only "dekita" is pitch black.
やめなよー！やめてあげなよー！
Stop it! Give it a rest!
黒好き？
Do you like black?
黒好きだよ。
I like black.
じゃあ次行きますか。
Shall we move on?
次はスバルちゃんの回答行きましょうか。
Let's go with Subaru-chan's answer next.
では、スバルちゃんの回答、オープン！
Now, Subaru-chan's answer, open!
みんなと出会えた♡
I met everyone ♡
おおー！一緒！
Oh! The same!
ちょっところさんと一緒、
これだったら嬉しいなと思いました。
It's similar to Koro-san's;
I thought it'd be nice if it was this.
どうかな？ミオしゃは。
How about Mio-sha?
じゃあミオちゃんのも開けていきたいと思います。
Then let's open Mio-chan's as well.
では、ミオちゃんの回答、オープン！
Now, Mio-chan's answer, open!
みんなで一緒に初詣に行ったこと
Going to the first shrine visit of the year
together with everyone
行ったね。
We did go.
ミオしゃ、行ったね。
Mio-sha, we went.
嬉しいけどね。あの時すごく幸せだったって言ってた、おかゆ。
It's nice, though. You said you were
very happy back then, Okayu.
僕はね、上京してきて初めて行ったんですよ、初詣に。
For me, it was the first time I went for
a shrine visit after moving to Tokyo.
それで、メンバーの中で誰か大吉出したらミオちゃん家泊まろうって言って、僕が大吉出して、みんなで泊まったんだよね。
And I said if someone among the members got a 'Daikichi',
we'd stay over at Mio-chan's place, and I got the 'Daikichi', so we all stayed over.
そう、すごい幸せだったって言ってた、確か。
Yeah, you said you were really happy, for sure.
あれ、それスバ…いないよ。
Wait, Suba... isn't there for that.
え、ミオしゃ、それスバとスバルちゃんいないよ。
Eh, Mio-sha, Suba and Subaru-chan aren't there.
いないよ！
I'm not there!
いないよ、それ、スバルいないよ、それ。
Subaru wasn't there for that.
むしろ、うちとおかゆの思い出だった、それ。
If anything, that was a memory of me and Okayu.
では回答見ていきましょう。
Now, let's look at the answer.
僕の答えた回答はこちらです。ダダン！
My answer is this. Ta-da!
正解
みんなとこうして出会えて超仲良くいられること
Correct Answer:
Being able to meet everyone like this and be super close
みんなとこうして出会えて超仲良くいられること！
Being able to meet everyone like this and be super close!
ちょっと待って、うちもうちも。あれ、ちょっと待って。
Wait a minute, I also... Hey, wait a minute.
ころさんとスバルちゃんが正解という判定だそうです。
It seems Koro-san and Subaru-chan are judged to be correct.
ちょっと待ってよ。うちもさ…
Wait a minute. I also...
ミオちゃん、初詣行ったんですか？
Mio-chan, did we go to a shrine visit?
初詣行って、おかゆ幸せだなーって…
We went to a shrine visit and Okayu was happy...
初詣に友達と一緒に行けて幸せだなーって言ってたんだよ！
You were saying you were happy to go to
a shrine visit with friends!
でもこの「みんな」っていうのはミオちゃんも入ってる「みんな」だからね。
But this 'everyone' includes Mio-chan too, you know.
おかゆー！
Okayu!
というわけで2名正解でした。
So, two people got it right.
残念だった。
That was a shame.
いいいね、正解してきたね。
Nice, you got it right.
何点もらえるの？
How many points do we get?
これはスタッフさん。1点だそうです。1点。
Staff says... one point. One point.
1点もらえましたよ。
We got one point.
じゃあまだ追いつけそうな感じする。
Then it feels like we can still catch up.
全然追いつきます。
You definitely can.
さあ、次のクイズ行きましょう！
Now, let's go to the next quiz!
問題
大空スバル・大神ミオ・戌神ころね、猫又おかゆが一緒に無人島に行くなら誰？
Question:
If Oozora Subaru, Ookami Mio, Inugami Korone,
and Nekomata Okayu were to go to a deserted island together, who would it be?
こんなの一択だよ！
There's only one choice for this!
こんなの全員が一択だろ！
Everyone would pick the same one, right!
これ難しいな。
This is difficult.
ちょっと待って、これ分かっちゃったんだけど。
Wait a minute, I think I figured this out.
僕も分かっちゃった。
I figured it out too.
何かな？これはどうなんだろう。
What is it? How will it go?
こういうことにしちゃう？こういうことにしちゃう。
Should I make it like this? I'll make it like this.
いい太いな、ころさん。
That's a nice bold line, Koro-san.
おデコレーションしてくれるの？
Are you going to decorate it?
お、みんな思いのまま書いてますね。
Oh, everyone is writing as they please.
あ、スバルちゃん自信がないんですか？
Ah, Subaru-chan, do you lack confidence?
あるよ！
I have it!
ミオちゃんも書いてますね。
Mio-chan is writing too.
おミオちゃんもデコレーション可愛いね。
Mio-chan's decoration is cute too.
これはもうさ、これはもうさ。
This is just... This is just...
ころさんはデコレーションの仕方がもう芸術的すぎんね。
Koro-san's way of decorating is just too artistic.
本当に美術館に飾りたいよ。飾って。
I really want to display it in a museum. Display it.
ああすごい！
Oh, amazing!
その青紫っぽい色好きだよ。
I like that bluish-purple color.
イルミネーションみたい。
It's like an illumination.
ありがとう。じゃあそろそろ出揃ってるので。
Thank you. Now, everyone is about ready.
今回の問題はみんなで一斉にオープンしたいと思います。
For this question, I'd like to open everyone's answers at once.
いいですか？
Are you ready?
では、回答オープン！
Now, answers open!
大空スバル！
Oozora Subaru!
大神ミオ！
Ookami Mio!
え、これなぞなぞじゃないんですか？
Eh, isn't this a riddle?
おかゆ
Okayu
どういうこと？どういうこと？
What do you mean? What do you mean?
何を言ってるんですか？
What are you talking about?
ころさん的にとんち利かせた結果ってこと？
So is this the result of you trying to be clever, Korone-san?
どういうとんち利かせ方だよ！
What kind of cleverness is that?!
その問題集にさ、書いてあったじゃん。最初にさ、
So, it was written in the question booklet, right? At first...
スバル、ミオ、ころね、おかゆ、無人島に行くのは誰？みたいに書いてあったじゃん。
...like "Subaru, Mio, Korone, Okayu, who will go to the desert island together?"
あー、右までが問題ってこと？
Ah, so you mean even the choices were part of the question?
そうで、これ、あの、無人島に行くのは僕だよっていうのかと思って。
Yeah, and I thought the answer was "The one who's going is me!"
なるほどねー。
I see!
ああ、そのパターンね。
Ah, that pattern.
じゃあもう一回問題見せてもらいましょう。
Well then, let's take another look at the question.
問題 大空スバル・大神ミオ・戌神ころね・猫又おかゆが一緒に無人島に行くなら誰？
Question: If Oozora Subaru, Ookami Mio, Inugami Korone, and Nekomata Okayu were to go to a desert island together, who would it be?
問題、大空スバル、大神ミオ、戌神ころね、猫又おかゆが...
Question: If Oozora Subaru, Ookami Mio, Inugami Korone, and Nekomata Okayu...
でも誰と一緒に無人島に行くことになっちゃうの？僕が抜けたら。
...but who would I end up going with if I were to leave?
確かに。
True.
とんち利かせすぎた結果。
The result of trying way too hard to be clever.
いやでも、分からない、猫又おかゆが一休の者だった場合は...
Well, we don't know. If Nekomata Okayu was like Ikkyu-san...
うわー、それありえる！
Whoa, that's possible!
それちょっと、ちょっと分かんないじゃん。
Wait, that's a bit... you never know.
ちょっとあり得るぞ。答え行きますよ。
It's possible. Here comes the answer.
答え、どん！
The answer is... Boom!
正解 大神ミオ
Correct: Ookami Mio
うわあああ！！
Whoa!!
ちょっと待って！
Wait, wait!
ミオしゃー！ミオしゃ！イェーイ！
Mio-sha! Mio-sha! Yay!
なんで！？
Why!?
納得いかない！
I don't accept this!
何撮ってんだ！
What are you taking!?
ふざけんな！
Don't mess with me!
でも聞いて、ミオしゃはさ...
But listen, Mio-sha...
食材がないと...
...if there's no food...
そうだよ。
That's right.
食材を調達してくればいいわけだから。
...she'll just procure the ingredients.
理由があるわけですね！
There's a reason for it!
まず、いいですか？じゃあスバルちゃんから行きますね。
First of all... okay? I'll start with Subaru-chan.
席戻ってください。まず、スバルちゃんと...
Please return to your seats. First, with Subaru-chan...
無人島に行ったのが冬だった場合、詰みます。それはガチ。
...if we went to the desert island in winter, we'd be stuck. For real.
スバルちゃんは全く動けなくなってしまいます。
Subaru-chan wouldn't be able to move at all.
で、ころさんの場合、無人島が超虫がいっぱいだった場合は、
In Korone's case, if the island was full of bugs...
もう戦力外と。
...she'd be out of action.
そうだ、そうだ。
That's true, that's true.
で、間取ってミオちゃんは、冬でも行けるし、
And in between them, Mio-chan can go in winter...
虫は苦手だけど一緒には頑張れるかなーって。
...and although she hates bugs, she'd try her best if we're together.
ま、頑張りはするかねー。
Well, I guess I'd try.
頑張るから四人で行こうじゃあ。
Since she'll try her best, let's all four of us go!
行かないから！
We're not going!
いいじゃん、これ、怖い。
Why not? This is scary.
行かないから！
We're not going!
みんなで補おうよ！
Let's all supplement each other!
夏になるよ、夏。
It'll be summer, summer.
まあ、理由がいろいろあるってことね。
Well, there are various reasons.
そっか。バランス型、バランス型だね。
I see. The balanced type.
僕なりにまあちょっといろいろ考えた結果、ミオちゃんかなーという感じですね。
Based on my own thoughts, I felt it should be Mio-chan.
納得の回答ですね。
That's a convincing answer.
イェーイ！ミオちゃんだった。
Yay! It was Mio-chan.
はい、では次の問題いきましょうかね。
Okay, let's move on to the next question.
はい、次の問題、どうぞ。ばじゃん！
Next question, please. Boom!
問題 猫又おかゆに聞いた、大空スバルの「可愛いと思うところ」はなに？
Question: What is Nekomata Okayu's answer for "something you think is cute about Oozora Subaru"?
猫又おかゆに聞いた、大空スバルの「可愛いと思うところ」はなに？
What is Okayu's answer for "something you think is cute about Oozora Subaru"?
あれ、なんて書いたっけな？
Wait, what did I write for that?
おい！おい、おめえ！
Hey! Hey, you!
台本、台本。と思うところ？
Script, script. "Something I think is cute"?
あー、あったあった。オッケーオッケー。でもおかゆめっちゃ褒めてくれるんだよなあ。
Ah, I remember! Okay. But Okayu compliments me so much.
え、ちなみにどういうところを褒められたか、ちょっと言ってみてよ。
By the way, tell us some of the things you've been complimented on.
おかゆ何でも褒めてくれるよ。
Okayu compliments me on anything!
え、そうなの？全肯定ってこと？
Is that so? A total validator?
何かな、何かな。えー、どこ？でもなんかね、すごいフェチズムの高いところとか褒めてくれる。
What could it be? Where? But you know, she compliments me on things where I have high fetishism.
え、そうなの？
Eh, is that so?
お尻柔らかくていいよねとかってこと？
Like, "Your butt is soft and nice," or something?
それは聞いたことないです。
I've never heard that one.
確かに可愛いところだ。
It's definitely a cute part.
えー、でもね、何だったっけな。か言ってたんだよなあ。
But what was it... she said it before.
これなんか自分で可愛いと思うところ発表するみたいで嫌なんですけど。
It feels embarrassing to announce where I think I'm cute myself.
でもね、当てに行きたくないですか？
But don't you want to try and get it right?
当てたい！
I want to!
そうですよ。なんなんだ。
That's it. What is it?
えー、可愛いと思って言ってったっけな。
Where did she say she thought I was cute...?
自分は難しいかもね。
It might be hard for yourself.
まあ、確かにな。
Well, true.
なんかでも、スバルちゃんはこういうところが良いところだよねってよくなんだっけな！
But Okayu often says "Subaru-chan is good in this way"... what was it!?
思い出して、思い出して！
Remember, remember!
思い出してくださいねー。
Please try to remember.
お、なかなか筆が進んでないですね、スバルちゃん。
Oh, your pen isn't moving much, Subaru-chan.
自分のことなのに。
Even though it's about yourself.
あ、ミオちゃんは書けました。
Oh, Mio-sha has finished writing.
書き終わってますね。ふむふむ。
She's finished. Hmm.
いやこれでしょう。多分。
It must be this. Probably.
絵が可愛い？
Is the drawing cute?
分かんない！
I don't know!
はい。なるほどねー。
Okay. I see.
ころさんも書き終わってますね。ふむふむ。あー、なるほどなるほど。
Korone-san has also finished. Hmm. I see, I see.
では、今回はころさんからオープンしていきたいと思います。
Well then, this time we'll start revealing from Korone-san.
あ、待って。帽子書いていい？
Wait, can I draw a hat?
あ、スバは帽子書こう。
Oh, Subaru's drawing a hat.
あ、いいね。みんなイラスト描いとるやん。
Nice, everyone is drawing illustrations.
イラスト描いてるみんな。
Everyone's drawing illustrations.
はい、ではいきたいと思います。
Okay, here we go.
ではころさんからオープン！
Korone-san, reveal!
パン！
Boom!
下を向きながらはにかむしぐさ？
Smiling shyly while looking down?
すごい細かい。
That's so specific.
すごい細かいぞ。
It's really specific.
そんなことしたっけ？
Did I do that?
そんなことしてる？
Do I do that?
え、なんか、スバルちゃんがワンピース着て、
Well, like, Subaru-chan was wearing a dress...
あ、ワンピース着てて。
Ah, she was wearing a dress.
ちょっとやってみて。
Try doing it.
え？
Eh?
で、ワンピース着てて、ねえねえ、
And, wearing a dress, "Hey, hey,"
そのワンピース超可愛いじゃん。似合ってるじゃん。
that dress is super cute. It looks good on you."
え、めっちゃ可愛いじゃん、って。
"Oh, it's so cute," she said.
うん、うん。
Yeah, yeah.
ちょっとやってみて。
Try doing it.
え？え？
Eh? Eh?
ありがとう...みたいな。
Like, "Thank you..."
ありがとう！
Thank you!
え、可愛い！
Oh, cute!
ちょっと待って。そんなことしたっけ、ころねの前で。
Wait a minute. Did I do that in front of Korone?
まあ、ちょっと恥ずかしがって誇張してますね。
Well, she's exaggerating a bit because she's shy.
あー、なるほどね。
Ah, I see.
おい、誇張してるんですか。
Hey, are you exaggerating?
はい。
Yes.
では、次ミオちゃんいきましょう。
Now, let's go to Mio-chan next.
はい。
Yes.
お願いします。
Please.
こちらです。
Here it is.
ごはんをたべるとねむくなっちゃうところ
Falling asleep after eating.
あるある。
That happens.
血糖値が...
The blood sugar level...
いつもそれ言うよね。
You always say that.
めっちゃ眠くなっちゃう、すぐ。
I get so sleepy, immediately.
血糖値ね。
Blood sugar level, right.
野菜からね。
From vegetables.
野菜から食べましょうね。
Let's eat vegetables first.
なるほどなるほど。
I see, I see.
じゃあ最後いきましょうか。
Then, let's go to the last one.
では、スバルちゃん、自分が思う可愛いところをお願いします。
Subaru-chan, please tell us what you think is cute about Okayu.
はい。
Yes.
素直なところ！
Her honesty!
すなおなところ！
素直なところ。
Her honesty.
何、このボタン？
What's this button?
これは帽子。おい、帽子だわ。
This is a hat. Hey, it's a hat.
おい、ボタン。
Hey, button.
ボタンかと思った、ごめん。
I thought it was a button, sorry.
これ、教え甲斐あるよね。
She's worth teaching.
帽子ってば！
It's a hat, I say!
これは、まあ布教されたら全部面白いって思うし、みたいな。
Well, if someone introduces me to something, I think everything is interesting, and so on.
そういう素直なところ。
That kind of honesty.
あー、そういうことね。
Ah, I see.
確かにね。
True.
言われてみれば確かに。
Now that you mention it, true.
あれ？
Wait?
なんかちょっと違うか？
Is it a bit different?
では、正解見ていきましょうか。
Then, let's see the correct answer.
では、ドン！
Here we go!
プレゼントもらったときにでっかい声で「え～～～！うれしい～～～！」って言うところ
When she gets a present, she says "Whaaat! I'm so happy!" in a loud voice.
あー！
Ah!
言う、言う！
She does!
言うよね。
She says that, right.
言うよ、言うよ。
She does, she does.
あらあら可愛い。
Oh my, cute.
あらあらじゃない。みんな言うじゃん。
It's not "oh my". Everyone says it.
いやだって、嬉しいんだもん。
Well, it's because I'm happy.
スバルさんのもらったプレゼント、めっちゃ楽しみに。
She really looks forward to the presents she receives from Subaru-san.
あらら。
Oh my.
今、スタッフさんからスバルさんはある意味正解なので...
Right now, the staff says Subaru-san is correct in a sense, so...
正解を与えるということで。
we'll give her the correct mark.
やったー！
Yay!
おめでとうございます。
Congratulations.
素直なんで。
Because I'm honest.
あ、これからもよろしくお願いします。
Ah, looking forward to working with you.
おめでとうございます。
Congratulations.
じゃあ、次行きますよ。
Now, let's go to the next one.
あー、そっか、それがあったか。
Ah, I see, that was it.
そうでしょ。
Right.
あっち、マジで、これ自分の番、覚悟したほうがいいですよ。
That, seriously, you should be prepared for your turn.
水あるから。
There's water.
マジで？
Seriously?
では、次の問題どうぞ。
Now, here's the next question.
猫又おかゆに聞いた、大神ミオの「PONだ」と思うところは、なに？
Okayu was asked: What do you think are Mio's 'PON' moments?
え、それ場面？
Eh, is it a scene?
まあ、PONだというところ。
Well, parts that are PON.
日常的にみたいな感じ？
Like, in daily life?
えー、ちょっと待って、そんな、おかゆの前でそんなポンしたっけ？
Eh, wait a minute, did I have such PON moments in front of Okayu?
ポンだというところ。
Parts that are PON.
どっちかっていうと僕のほうがポンしまくってるからね。
If anything, I'm the one having PON moments all the time.
え、なんだろう。
Eh, what could it be?
トイレから出てきたらスカートが全部パンツの中に入ってたり...
Coming out of the toilet with the skirt tucked into the panties...
最初からそれ出んじゃん。
That comes out from the start.
カボチャパンツみたいになってたところ。
The part where it looked like pumpkin pants.
「ミオちゃんお待たせー」って言って出てきたらね。
Coming out saying "Mio-chan, sorry for the wait".
なんかほとんど入ってるっていう。
It was almost all tucked in.
最初からそれ出んじゃん、全部パンツの中。
That comes out from the start, all in the panties.
いや待って、それで書き消されちゃうよ。
Wait, that will overwrite it.
これぞミオちゃんのポンだからね。
This is Mio-chan's PON.
これをミオちゃんのポンだと思ってる僕の...
This is what I think is Mio-chan's PON...
そうだよ。
Yes.
いや、ポン、内緒にしてたのに。
No, I was keeping my PON moments a secret.
はい、書き始めてくださいね。
Yes, please start writing.
内緒にしてたのに！
I was keeping it a secret!
もう手遅れだよ、ミオしゃ。
It's too late, Mio-sha.
うちのポンなところ。
My PON moments.
何ですかね、何ですかね。
What could it be, what could it be?
マジで思いつかん。
I really can't think of any.
何かな何かな。
What is it, what is it?
一応僕も答え見とこう。
I'll check the answer too.
どんなところか。
What kind of part.
どんなところですよ。
What kind of part it is.
まあ、ミオちゃんはいつもね、僕たちのこと引っ張ってくれてる存在だから。
Well, Mio-chan is always someone who leads us.
ピンとは来ないよね。
It doesn't immediately ring a bell, right.
来ない。すぐは思い浮かばないよね。
No. It doesn't come to mind immediately.
僕もかなり悩みました。
I also struggled quite a bit.
ポンなところ。
PON moments.
ミオちゃんのポンなところか。
Mio-chan's PON moments.
思い出せないけどリスナーの皆さんはどうですか？
I can't remember, but how about the listeners?
え、ちょっと見てみましょうか。
Eh, let's take a look.
えー、そんな思いつく、みんな。
Eh, everyone can think of that.
なるほど。
I see.
ポンな、ははは、リスナーの皆さんは、
PON, hahaha, the listeners are...
この間ペコラと刺身についている菊の花が食べれると知らなかったみたいな、なんかそんなこと書いてましたね。
Something about not knowing that the chrysanthemum flower on sashimi could be eaten, like she was talking to Pekora about it.
あー、この間。
Ah, recently.
刺身についてるやつをタンポポだとずっと信じてたのに、あれは菊の花だということを最近知りました。
I always believed that the thing on sashimi was a dandelion, but I recently learned that it's a chrysanthemum flower.
そうなんだ。
Is that so.
あったね。
That happened.
おタンポポ事件。
The O-Tanpopo Incident.
確かにおタンポポって言ってた。
She definitely said "O-Tanpopo".
おタンポポ事件。さあ、どうですか皆さん、書き終わりましたか？
The O-Tanpopo Incident. Well, how about you all, have you finished writing?
まあ僕もね めっちゃ迷って書きましたから
Well, I too had a lot of trouble deciding what to write.
よいしょ よいしょ。
Yoisho, yoisho.
どうかな どうかな？
I wonder how it'll be? I wonder how it'll be?
いいですか そろそろじゃあ
Are you ready? Soon, then?
いっちゃいますよ
I'm going to go ahead.
わかんない！
I don't know!
わかんないんだよ、これ！
I don't know this!
じゃあ一斉にオープンしていきましょう
Then let's open them all at once.
では 回答オープン！
Now, answers open!
え、ころねさん、何それ？
Eh, Korone-san, what is that?
えええ！？
Ehhh!?
ころね、何それ？
Korone, what is that?
そして これは天パだから
And this is Tempa, so...
違う違う 違う違う...
No, no, no, no...
違う、なんか、もうちょっとさ、あの...
No, like, a bit more, you know...
サザエさんかい
Are you Sazae-san!?
そんな時あったか？
Was there such a time?
わかんない。何かなと思って。ミオさんいつもシャキっとしてるよ？
I don't know. I was wondering. Mio-san is always so sharp.
そう。
Right.
だから思いつかなかったから
So since I couldn't think of anything...
なるほどね。まさかのこの髪型もカーラーでつけてるのかって。
I see. Like, maybe even this hairstyle is held by curlers?
そんなことそっち？
That's what you thought?
なるほどね
I see.
天パだよ、これ
This is Tempa.
なるほどね
I see.
わざわざ頭にカーラーをつけてきたね
She went through the trouble of putting curlers on her head.
じゃあミオちゃん行こうか
Then let's go with Mio-chan.
よく言い間違いをするところ
She often makes slips of the tongue.
はい はい はい はい
I see, I see.
たまにね ちょっとやっちゃうみたいなね
Like, she sometimes does it.
なるほどね。まあよくあるポンですね
I see. Well, that's a common PON.
そうですね
That's true.
じゃあスバルちゃんは？
Then Subaru-chan?
そうめんASMRとかを突然やりだす
Suddenly starts doing somen ASMR or something.
これポンなん！？
Is this a PON!?
いやいやいやいや、普段しっかりしてるから！
No no no no, because she's usually so solid!
なるほどね、そういうことをやるんだ！みたいな
I see, it's like "Oh, she does that kind of thing!"
意外性ってこと？
You mean the unexpectedness?
意外性！
Unexpectedness!
ちょっとポン可愛いっていうことで。ポン可愛いってことミオしゃ
Like, it's a bit of a cute PON. It's a cute PON, Mio-sha.
なるほどね
I see.
あーそうなのね。それ。では正解見ていきましょう。ドン！
Oh, I see. That's it. Now let's see the correct answer. Bam!
正解！
Correct answer!
思い浮かばなかったので想像で答えます
I couldn't think of anything, so I'll answer with my imagination.
たまにピン留めをたくあんと間違えて食べている
She sometimes mistakes a hairclip for a pickled radish and eats it.
当たるかこんなん！
How am I supposed to guess that!
いや、捏造しちゃうよ
No way, she's making stuff up.
てか思い浮かばないって書いたら正解だったわけでしょう？
So if we wrote "I can't think of anything", we would have been correct?
いやいやいや
No no no.
あー確かに
Ah, true.
あー確かに。そうだ。だってみんなで最初言ってたじゃん
Ah, true. That's right. Because we all said it at the start.
思い浮かばないよねって
Like "We can't think of anything".
え、でも頭のカーラーを食べるって書いてたら正解だったってこと？
Wait, so if I wrote "Eating the curlers on her head", would that have been correct?
それカーラーじゃねえだろ！
That's not a curler!
まあでも捏造してるって意味ではまあ近いよね。
Well, in the sense that it's made up, it's close.
捏造した人のポンを
Making up someone's PON.
そっか
I see.
あーお腹空いたなー。もう... あれ？ これたくあんじゃなかったわ、っていうこと？
"Oh, I'm hungry. Oh... wait? This wasn't a pickled radish", is what you mean?
いや すげえ空気になるわ そんなもの食べられたら
Man, the atmosphere would be so weird if someone ate that.
ごめんね滑らせちゃって
Sorry for making a joke fall flat.
誰も突っ込めないよそんなこと
No one can point that out.
違う、ミオしゃがやってると尚更突っ込めないよな
No, it's especially hard to point out if Mio-sha is doing it.
確かにね
True.
スバルちゃんがもう割って入って突っ込んでいかないと
Subaru-chan has to break in and point it out.
ちょちょちょちょ！
Whoa whoa whoa!
それ違いますよ！っていかないと
"That's not it!" I'd have to go.
え、ミオしゃ可愛いとかありな
Oh, or "Mio-sha is cute".
やってないから！違う違う。
I don't do that! No, no.
これ本当のうちじゃないから。想像だからこれ。そうそうそう。
This isn't the real me. It's an imagination. Right, right, right.
ということで、正解者はなしということで次が最後の問題です
So, there was no winner, and next is the final question.
いいですか？
Are you ready?
問題どうぞ
Here is the question.
猫又おかゆに聞いた、
I asked Nekomata Okayu,
戌神ころねの尊敬できるところは何？
what is the point that you respect about Inugami Korone?
これ言ってた！
She said this!
え、言ってた？
Eh, she did?
何かな 何かな
I wonder what it is, I wonder what it is.
え、一つしか思い浮かばないんだけど
Eh, I can only think of one thing though.
何かなー
I wonder what it is.
え、これわかる！
Eh, I know this!
お、お。スバルちゃん筆が進んでおりません
Oh, oh. Subaru-chan's pen is not moving.
うーん...
Hmm...
ミオさんは？
How about Mio-san?
あ！
Ah!
書き進めております
She's writing away.
これしか思い浮かばないんだけど
I can only think of this though.
待って、僕もなんて書いたかな。でも確かに
Wait, what did I write? But certainly...
ねえ、これ。これしか思いつかん
Hey, this. I can only think of this.
いや、だっても僕なんて書いたか忘れちゃったんよ、多すぎて。
No, because I've forgotten what I wrote, there were so many.
そうそうそう。
Right, right, right.
そっか そうなんだ
I see, is that so?
えーっと、これ。
Uhh, this.
あ、今スタッフさんから、これ最後の問題なんで1億点だそうですよ
Ah, the staff just said that since this is the last question, it's worth 100 million points.
勝ちだ！
I win!
みんながこれ違うって言われたら「でも言ってたよ」って
If everyone says this is wrong, I'll say "But I said it".
だから、そのうちの一つだからね。今回特出して一つ選んでるわけだから
So, it's one of them. I've specially chosen one this time.
そっか
I see.
さあ、どうかな
Now, how is it going?
え、じゃあこれかな
Eh, then maybe this?
何かな 何かな 何かな 何かな...
I wonder what it is, I wonder what it is...
何かな、何かな...
I wonder what it is...
猫又おかゆに聞いた、大神ミオの「PONだ」と思うところはなに？
What is Mio's "PON" according to Okayu?
猫又おかゆに聞いた、戌神ころねの「尊敬できるところ」はなに？
What is the point that Okayu respects about Inugami Korone?
はい！何においても天才！
Yes! A genius in everything!
え、嬉しい。
Oh, I'm happy.
はい！
Yes!
えー、どんなに怒っても最後は許しちゃうところ。
Uh, how no matter how much I'm angry, I end up forgiving her in the end.
あー、そうだね。
Ah, that's right.
懐まで深いよね。
She's so broad-minded.
そうだね。確かに。
Yeah. Certainly.
そして...
And...
最後は、水まわりの掃除を毎日しているとこー！
Finally, how she cleans the bathroom and kitchen every day!
えー！それは尊敬する！
Whoa! I respect that!
それは尊敬する！すごい！
I respect that! Amazing!
でもマジでさ、これ、おかゆ、おかゆから聞いたことある、この話。
But seriously, I've heard this from Okayu before.
おかゆが...
Okayu said...
正解かもしれない、これ。
This might be the correct answer.
ころさんは毎日掃除しているから、すごいよねって...
Koro-san is amazing because she cleans every day...
あ、なるほどな。
Oh, I see.
正解 遊びに行くと絶対絶対絶対絶対絶対部屋がきれい
Correct: When I go over, the room is absolutely absolutely absolutely absolutely absolutely clean.
ということで、じゃあ、行きますよ。
With that, let's go.
はい、回答お願いします。
Please show the answer.
ドン、だ！
Don!
正解。遊びに行くと絶対絶対絶対絶対部屋がきれい。
Correct. When I go over, her room is absolutely absolutely absolutely absolutely clean.
ということで、ころさん正解ー！
So, Koro-san is correct!
おかゆが言ってた！めっちゃ言ってた！
Okayu said it! She said it so much!
出てきて、壁から出てきて。これはダメだわ、これ。
Come on, come out from behind the booth. This is it.
これ、よく言ってるじゃん。
You say this often.
これも、幅広く。これ、言ってるけど、今回選んだのはこれっていうね。
This is also common. I say it, but this is the one I chose this time.
なるほどね。
I see.
え、じゃあ、ころねが1億点ってこと？
Wait, so Korone gets 100 million points?
そうですよ。1億点。
That's right. 100 million points.
では、結果発表の前に、
Before the result announcement...
えーと、一曲聴いてもらうみたいですよ。
Uh, it seems we'll hear a song.
おー！何なに？
Oh! What is it?
猫又おかゆで『もぐもぐYUMMY！』。
Nekomata Okayu, 'Mogu Mogu Yummy!'.
もぐもぐ
Mogu mogu
森羅万象の 悪戦苦闘も
Even the struggles of all creation
マヨネーズかけたら 大体美味しくなる
Usually become delicious if you add mayonnaise
君が泣いても お腹は空くよ
Even if you cry, I'll still get hungry
消化できなかった ごめんごめん
I couldn't digest it, sorry sorry
酸いも甘いも 勝手に食べて
Eating sour and sweet things as I please
ご迷惑おかけして います
I am causing some trouble
パクチーな掟 変な味のジュース
Coriander-flavored rules, weird-tasting juice
心を無にして 飲み込みます
Emptying my mind and swallowing them
ああ 混沌 情報過多のレストランで
Ah, in this chaotic restaurant of information overload
嘘っぱちのメニューに お茶こぼして
Spilling tea over the fake menu
君ともぐもぐ(あーん) もぐもぐ(あーん)
Mogu mogu with you (ahhh), mogu mogu (ahhh)
追撃戦の 真ん中でもぐもぐ
Mogu mogu in the middle of a pursuit
死にもろ腹ペコ この群れ
Starving to death, this crowd
満腹になる未来 お祈っているよ
Praying for a future where we're full
もぐもぐ(あーん) もぐもぐ(あーん)
Mogu mogu (ahhh), mogu mogu (ahhh)
世界が終わる 前に
Before the world ends...
もぐもぐ YUMMY マジ神
Mogu mogu Yummy, seriously divine
ヤムヤム ありのまんま
Yum yum, just as I am
もぐもぐ YUMMY マジ神
Mogu mogu Yummy, seriously divine
今夜を味わうんだ 旨い旨い
Savoring tonight, tasty, tasty
理論武装の ミルフィーユサンド (サンド)
A theory-armed mille-feuille sandwich (sandwich)
匿名希望の オーロラソース (ソース)
An anonymous-desired aurora sauce (source)
大雑把な味付け お目に見てよ
Look at my rough seasoning
美味しくなったら オッケーオッケー
If it becomes tasty, then okay, okay
良いも悪いも いっぱい食べて
Eating lots of good and bad things
汚れた口元 拭います
I'll wipe my dirty mouth
おにぎりパンケーキ 豪華なフルコース
Rice balls, pancakes, a luxurious full-course meal
罠を疑い 気をつけます
Suspecting a trap and being careful
ああ 空想 流行り廃りのバイキングで
Ah, at this fantasy buffet of trends
特異日と絶品料理 分け合って
Sharing special days and exquisite dishes
君ともぐもぐ(あーん) もぐもぐ(あーん)
Mogu mogu with you (ahhh), mogu mogu (ahhh)
デスゲームの 教室でもぐもぐ
Mogu mogu in the death game classroom
死にもろ腹ペコ この群れ
Starving to death, this crowd
仲の良い君と 生き残れたらいいな
I hope I can survive with you, my good friend
もぐもぐ(あーん) もぐもぐ(あーん)
Mogu mogu (ahhh), mogu mogu (ahhh)
数年後も この場所で
Even years later, at this place...
もぐもぐ YUMMY マジ神
Mogu mogu Yummy, seriously divine
今夜の晩御飯は
Tonight's dinner is...
もぐもぐ YUMMY マジ神
Mogu mogu Yummy, seriously divine
次はお前の番だ もぐもぐ YUMMY マジ神
Next is your turn, mogu mogu Yummy, seriously divine
ヤムヤム ありのまんま
Yum yum, just as I am
もぐもぐ YUMMY マジ神
Mogu mogu Yummy, seriously divine
この世を味わうんだ 旨い旨い
Savoring this world, tasty, tasty
もぐもぐもぐもぐ... もぐもぐヤミー
Mogu mogu mogu mogu... Mogu mogu Yummy
結果発表！
Result announcement!
なに？
What?
それでは、結果発表。
Now, for the result announcement.
結果発表。
Result announcement.
結果発表！
Result announcement!
さ、それでは注目の結果発表です。
Now, let's announce the results everyone's been waiting for.
猫又おかゆのことを最も理解しているのは誰なのか。
Who understands Nekomata Okayu the best?
全員の得点、オープン！
Everyone's scores, open!
うわぁぁ！
Whoa!
バグってるって！
It's bugged!
ころねのバグってるって、これ！
Korone's is bugged!
おかしい。桁違いな奴が。
Something's wrong. One's on a completely different level.
馬鹿みたいなんですけど！
It's ridiculous!
まぁ、ちょっとね、スバルちゃんとミオちゃんは、2点と1点というちょっとカスみたいな...
Well, Subaru and Mio got 2 and 1 point, which is kind of trashy...
カス言うな！
Don't call us trash!
世界大会3つ目だぜ、こっちは！
I've won three world championships!
負け犬の遠吠えは聞こえないということで、次に参ります。
I can't hear the losers' howling, so let's move on.
何言いよん、お前。
What are you talking about?
はい、優勝した戌神ころねさんには、
Yes, to the winner, Inugami Korone-san,
番組特製「猫又おかゆがもっと好きになるドリンク」を飲んでいただきます！
you will drink the program's special "Drink to Make You Like Nekomata Okayu More"!
優勝した人が飲むの？
The winner drinks it?
いいの？
Is it okay?
もっと好きになっちゃうじゃん。
I'll just like you even more.
意外だわ、意外。
How unexpected.
ミオちゃんとスバルちゃんに、飲んでもらいますよ。
Mio and Subaru will be the ones drinking it.
言ったものの、なんか嫌な気持ちになってきた。
I suggested it, but now I'm feeling uneasy.
ヤバい気がしてきた。
I'm getting a bad feeling about this.
ミオちゃん飲んで。スバル飲んで。
Drink it, Mio. Drink it, Subaru.
スタッフさん、ドリンクの準備をしてもらっていいですか？
Staff, can you get the drinks ready?
嫌な予感しかしないんだけど。
I have nothing but a bad feeling about this.
ころさんはね、十分僕のこと好きだから飲まなくていいよ。
Koro-san already likes me enough, so she doesn't need to drink it.
ドリンク準備されたということで。
The drinks are ready.
うわぁ、なんか手に持ってる！色やべぇ！
Whoa, they're holding something! The color is crazy!
なんだこれ！
What is this!
色やばすぎ。
The color is too much.
ミオちゃんあげる。やめてよ。うちも持ってる。ノルマだ、ノルマこれ。
I'll give it to Mio. Stop it. I have one too. It's a quota, it's a quota.
美味しそうだよね。
It looks delicious, doesn't it?
ライムみたいなさ。
Like lime.
じゃあ、早速飲んでください！
Now, please drink up!
ミオちゃんがスバルに飲ませて、スバルがミオちゃんに飲ませるから。
Mio will feed Subaru, and Subaru will feed Mio.
ミオしゃ？
Miosha?
かけちゃうかもしれん。
I might spill it.
はーい、飲んでくださーい。
Alright, drink up.
どうですか？
How is it?
美味しいですか？
Is it good?
どんな味？
How does it taste?
ん、でも悪くないぞ。
Hmm, it's not bad.
お、でもなんかスッキリしてて美味しいかも。
Oh, it's kind of refreshing and might be good.
美味しいかも！
It might be good!
マジか。美味しいんだったら飲みたい。
Really? If it's good, I want to drink it.
スムージーみたいな感じ。
It's like a smoothie.
でもこれで僕のこと大好きになれるなら、めちゃめちゃいいですよね。
But if this makes you love me, that's great.
確かにお手軽かも。
It is pretty convenient.
ころさんにも飲んでもらいますか。
Shall we have Koro-san drink some too?
お手軽、お手軽。いいの？どうぞ。
Convenient, convenient. Is it okay? Go ahead.
お、ころねも。特製ジュース。美味しいかな、これ。
Oh, Korone too. The special juice. I wonder if it's good.
直で！？
Directly!?
美味しい？
Is it good?
美味しい。
It's good.
でしょう！
Right!
以上、「猫又おかゆ、わかり手グランプリ」でした！
That was the "Nekomata Okayu Understander Grand Prix"!
オエェェェ！苦しい！
Blegh! It hurts!
ゲロ吐き。
I'm gonna puke.
毒の王子さま
作詞・作曲・編曲：奏音64
Poisonous Prince
Lyrics, Composition, Arrangement: Kanon64
君が抱えてる 心の傷口に
On the wounds of your heart that you carry
優しいフリの 嘘を擦り込んでいく
I rub in lies that pretend to be kind
疑いもせずに 偽善とも知らずに
Without a doubt, without knowing it's hypocrisy
寄り添うことが 君の生き甲斐
Cuddling close is your reason for living
ツルリ ドロリ 引き摺り込んで
Slipping, dripping, dragging you in
戻れない底へ 落としてあげる
I'll drop you to the bottom where you can't return
いつか君が 僕だけ求めて
Someday, you'll seek only me
泣く姿を見て
Seeing you crying
泣く姿を見て みたい
I want to see you crying
君が望むなら 僕は王子さま
If that's what you wish, I am a prince
目覚めのキスなら 毒入りの愛で
If it's a waking kiss, it's with poisoned love
騙してあげるよ 楽になれるなら
I'll deceive you, if it makes it easier
嘘は毒にも 薬にもなる
Lies can be both poison and medicine
だから、悪くはないでしょう？
So, it's not bad, right?
踏み出す足が曲がる 不揃いな関係も
My stepping feet curve, even our mismatched relationship...
僕は気付く 嘘で縫い合わせる
...I realize, I'm sewing it together with lies.
気付かなくていい 本当のことなんて
You don't have to notice. Such a thing as the truth...
知らない 嘘はないのと同じ
...I don't know it. It's the same as there being no lies.
するり とろり 飲みやすいように
Smoothly, meltily, so it's easy to drink.
甘く溶かした薬みたいだ
Like a medicine melted sweet.
まるで お菓子のように見せかけて
Pretending as if it were candy...
君に口移す 偽薬
...mouth-to-mouth, I give you a placebo.
極上の夜だけ君はお姫様
Only on the finest nights are you a princess.
硝子の靴履き死ぬまでダンスを
Wearing glass slippers, dance until you die.
愛してあげるよ 苦しまないように
I'll love you, so you don't suffer.
嘘は何より君を救える
Lies can save you more than anything.
誰が僕を咎めるの？
Who is going to blame me?
清く正しい真実の方が
The pure and righteous truth is...
余程残酷な毒になるでしょう
...bound to be a far more cruel poison.
午前0時 眠れないほどに
12:00 AM, to the point I can't sleep...
生きることに怯えてる
...I'm frightened of living.
毒はどちら？ 君が望むなら
Which one is the poison? If you desire it...
僕は王子様 目覚めのキスなら
I am your Prince Charming. If it's a waking kiss...
毒入りの愛で演じてあげるよ
...I'll play the part with poison-filled love.
魔法が解けるまで 僕は毒でも
Until the magic breaks, even if I'm poison...
薬でもいい それも悪くない
...or medicine, that's fine too. That's not so bad.
嘘つきな毒の王子さま
The lying Poison Prince.
夢を語らずに現を語るけれど
I don't talk about dreams, I talk about reality, but...
僕だけに君は笑う
You smile only at me.
それだけは嘘じゃない真実
That alone is the truth, not a lie.
だから、悪くないでしょう？
So, it's not so bad, right?
それでいいよ
That's fine.
いっそ屍になって 転がってたいけど
I'd rather be a corpse and just roll around, but...
みっともないから 口から出る「大丈夫」
...it's pathetic, so 'I'm okay' comes out of my mouth.
透明な街をすり抜け 傷跡晒したまま
Slipping through the transparent city, with my scars still exposed...
耳障りメトロのメロディ こんな僕も肯定して
...the harsh melody of the metro, please affirm even someone like me.
感情も心臓も 値段が付くらしいね
Apparently, both emotions and hearts have a price tag.
エンドレスな新規リスナー いくらですか？ 幸せとは
Endless new listeners, how much is it? What is happiness?
神様 ウザったい恥を捨てたら
God, if I throw away this annoying shame...
並べた嘘にキスしよう
...let's kiss the lies I've lined up.
I LOVE U 最底辺の楽園さ
I LOVE U, it's the lowest-tier paradise.
孤独と指絡ませ アデュー、サロー
Intertwining fingers with loneliness, Adieu, Salow.
何者でもない僕を せめて慰めてよ
At least comfort me, for I am a nobody.
アデュー、サロー
Adieu, Salow.
簡単なことも出来ずに 息を止めて歩いた
Unable to do even simple things, I walked while holding my breath.
愛くるしいあの子は いつの間にか笑えなくなっちゃった
That adorable girl, before she knew it, she could no longer smile.
「もしもし、本当こっち側じゃなくて良かったよ。」
“Hello? I’m really glad I’m not on this side.”
まだ泣いてんだこの人生は 曇り模様 晴れ間探し
This life is still crying, a cloudy pattern searching for a break in the clouds.
強がってるわけじゃない 誰か僕を見てよ
I'm not trying to act tough, someone please look at me.
見つけて
Find me.
ウザったい恥を捨てたら 並べた嘘にキスしよう
If I throw away this annoying shame, let's kiss the lies I've lined up.
I LOVE U 承認に飢えた亡霊さ
I LOVE U, I'm a ghost starved for validation.
負け惜しみで叫んだ アデュー、サロー
Shouted out of sour grapes, Adieu, Salow.
何者でもない僕を
For me, who is a nobody...
慰める奴はいない
...there is no one to comfort me.
アデュー、サロー
Adieu, Salow.
はい、ということで、改めてここまで聴いてくださった皆さん、
Yes, and once again, to everyone who's been listening so far,
ねこまたおかゆですよ〜
it's Nekomata Okayu!
アデューサロン聴いてくださってありがとうございました
Thank you for listening to "Adieu Salon."
やっぱね、アデューサロンは、
You know, for "Adieu Salon,"
プルル〜って電話が来るところ、やっぱみんな大好きだと思うんで
I think everyone really loves the part where the phone rings.
ちょっとね、電話のセリフを言うのが、ちょっと一番の山場というか、ね
Saying the lines on the phone is like the biggest highlight, or something like that.
一番ドキドキしながら、
I always feel like it's the part where I'm most nervous
こう歌うというか喋るところだなといつも思っております
while singing or talking.
はい。ということでですね、
Yes. So,
あの〜今までオリジナル曲たくさん歌わせていただいたんですが...
I've performed many original songs so far, but...
ここからですね、なんとまだ未発表のオリジナル曲の発表となります！
From here, I'm going to announce a brand new original song!
え〜、いいですか？発表しちゃっていいですか？
Um, is it okay? Can I go ahead and announce it?
では、え〜ドゥルルルルルルルル... はい！ジャン！
Then, um... [drumroll]... Yes! Ta-da!
え〜今回新しく歌わせていただきます、「毒杯スワロウ」！
The new song I'll be singing is "Doku-Hai Swallow"!
お〜、こちらの楽曲...
Oh, this song...
あ、なんか暗くなっちゃったｗ
Ah, it's suddenly gotten dark (lol).
待って待って、待って、まだ喋りたいことあるから、
Wait, wait! I still have more to say.
あの、こちらの楽曲は...
Um, this song...
え〜僕も「歌ってみた」で歌わせていただいている「失楽ペトリ」という楽曲を作っている、
It was written for me by Nanahoshi Kangengakudan, who also created "Shitsuraku Petri,"
七星管弦楽団さんという方に書き下ろししていただきました！
a song I've covered before!
じゃあ、あの照明係さん、今から歌いますんで、え〜電気消してもらっていいですよ
Alright, lighting staff, I'm going to sing now, so you can turn off the lights.
では、聴いてください、「毒杯スワロウ」！
Now, please listen to "Doku-Hai Swallow"!
毒杯スワロウ / 作詞：岩見 陸 作曲・編曲：七星管弦楽団
Doku-Hai Swallow / Lyrics: Iwami Riku; Composition/Arrangement: Nanahoshi Kangengakudan
誂えた業に乗せ
Riding on a custom-made fate
ひっそりと爪を研いでいる
Quietly sharpening my claws
眠りさえ化け物に
Even sleep becomes a monster
香り纏わせお前の喉に
Wearing a scent, into your throat
この身体のどこかに生まれ落ちたなら
If I were born somewhere in this body
何者にも食せぬ 毒 毒 毒
Uneatable by anyone - poison, poison, poison
似たような不真面目と嗅ぎ回られもしようが
They might sniff around for similar insincerity
喉から手が出るほど 毒 毒 毒
Craving it with all my soul - poison, poison, poison
嗚呼 蓮に蓮にと 構えていた
Ah, prepared for anything,
両刃の剣
a double-edged sword
切っ先に立って じっとしていられるのなら
If you can stand on the tip and stay still
のぞみは甘い
Expectations are sweet
Swallow Swallow その唇で
Swallow, swallow, with those lips
深く患った病を もとめ啄む
Seeking and pecking at a deeply rooted illness
願うまま茨を 着こなせればと
Hoping I could wear the thorns as I wish
身柄が狩るのどを鳴らす
My body purrs at the hunt
何食わぬ顔にさえ
Even with an innocent face
こっそり牙を宿していたい
I want to secretly harbor fangs
かじりつきたいだけで
Just wanting to bite into it
吠えてはみてもお前のように
Even if I bark, not like you
その甲斐など何処に隠し持っていたのか
Where were you hiding such worthiness?
五臓六腑を惑わせる 毒 毒 毒
Confusing my very core - poison, poison, poison
悪し様に噂を そばだてられもしようが
They might prick up their ears at ill-natured rumors
生唾滴るほど 毒 毒 毒
Making mouths water - poison, poison, poison
嗚呼 善かり善かれと 紡いでいた
Ah, a spoiled poisonous cup
甘ったれの毒杯
spun for the sake of goodness
退廃に浸して 引導渡せるのなら
If I can soak in decadence and say the final rites
此の世は辛い
This world is bitter
Swallow Swallow ただ渇いては
Swallow, swallow, just thirsting
低く高笑った礼も 舌で転がす
Rolling a low-pitched laugh of thanks on my tongue
手負いのまま路傍を はばたければと
Hoping I could flap along the roadside while wounded
指をくわえ見ているか
Are you watching with envy?
今日も今日とて
Today, just like any other day
口元に修羅を塗りたくる
Smearing battle onto my lips
Swallow Swallow まだ耳元で
Swallow, swallow, still at the ear
暗くぬかるんだ迷いも 束の間の影
Dark, muddy hesitation is but a fleeting shadow
思うまま綺麗事を 抱きしめればと
Hoping I could embrace platitudes as I wish
地べたを這う世界が 泣き止まぬまま
While the world crawling on the ground won't stop crying
Swallow Swallow その唇で
Swallow, swallow, with those lips
深く患った病を もとめ啄む
Seeking and pecking at a deeply rooted illness
願うまま茨を 着こなせればと
Hoping I could wear the thorns as I wish
身柄が狩るのどを鳴らす
My body purrs at the hunt
香り惑わせ お前の様に
The scent leading me astray, just like you
この体の何処かに 生まれ持っていたらな
If only I were born with it somewhere in this body
何も何も食せぬ 毒 毒 毒
Consuming nothing at all, poison, poison, poison
いたよな旨さと 掻き回られもしようか
With that delicious flavor, I'll be stirred up too
喉から手が出る程 毒 毒 毒
Desperately wanting it, poison, poison, poison
蓮に蓮にと 構えていた
Keeping a cautious distance
諸刃の剣
A double-edged sword
切先立って じといられるのなら
If I can stay still on the edge
のぞみ迎え
Welcoming my desire
swallow, swallow その唇で
swallow, swallow with those lips
深くわずらう病を
The deep-seated illness
求めついばむ
Seeking and pecking at it
願うまま荊をこなせればと
Hoping to overcome the thorns as I wish
身柄掲げる程 癒やす
Healing as if holding up my body
何食わぬ顔して
With an innocent face
こっそり牙を宿していた
Secretly hiding my fangs
囓り付き平らげて
Biting down and finishing it off
はーい！
Hi everyone!
先程流れたVTRの通り、
As you saw in the VTR just now,
なんと僕の初めての有観客ソロライブ、
my very first solo live concert with an audience,
猫又おかゆ 1st Live『ぽいずにゃ〜しんどろーむ』
Nekomata Okayu 1st Live "POISONYA SYNDROME"
supported by ブシロードが、
supported by Bushiroad,
2022年9月30日、立川ステージガーデンで
will be held on September 30, 2022,
開催されることになじゅました！
at Tachikawa Stage Garden!
噛んだー！
I tripped over my words!
えー、ここからたくさんの台本を読むことになるので、
Well, I have a lot of script to read from here on out,
噛んだら皆さん笑顔で許してください。
so if I mess up, please forgive me with a smile.
では参ります。
Here we go.
キービジュアルイラストは神岡ちろるママ、
The key visual illustration is by Kamioka Chirol-mama,
ロゴとデザインは藤宮藍先生が担当されました。
and the logo and design were by Fujimiya Ai-sensei.
ライブのハッシュタグは #おかゆソロライブ でお願いします。
Please use the hashtag #おかゆソロライブ for the live concert.
いや、やっと発表できたよ！
Man, I finally got to announce it!
おにぎりゃーのみんなにはね、なんか色々大変だーとか言ってたけど、
I kept telling all the Onigirya that things were busy and tough,
何が大変なのかっていう話まではね、ちょっとできなかったんですけど、
but I couldn't really say exactly why until now...
そうなんです！僕のソロライブがあるんだよ、
That's right! I'm having a solo live concert,
みんな、みんなー！すごいよね。
everyone, everyone! Isn't it amazing?
えー、このね、描き下ろしていただいたイラストも、ロゴも
This specially drawn illustration and the logo
めちゃくちゃ可愛いんで、
are just so incredibly cute,
なめるように、もう、なめるように、皆さん見てくださいね。
so please take a really, really good look at them, everyone.
超可愛いんで。
Because they're super cute.
えー、では次読んでいきますよ。
Alright, I'll read the next part.
この後21時から現地の会場チケットの1次先行抽選、
Starting today at 21:00, the first advance lottery for venue tickets
そして配信チケットの販売がスタートします！ふぅ。
and the sale of streaming tickets will begin! *Whew*
今回現地の会場チケット1次先行は、
This first advance lottery for venue tickets
ホロライブ公式ファンクラブ先行となるので、
will be for Hololive Official Fan Club members,
お申し込みにはファンクラブへの加入が必要になります。
so you'll need to join the fan club to apply.
抽選受付になるので、焦らずに申し込んでね。
It's a lottery system, so take your time and apply.
また、配信チケットは、SPWNとLINE LIVE-VIEWINGの
Also, for streaming tickets, we have two platforms:
2つのプラットフォームを用意してもらいました。
SPWN and LINE LIVE-VIEWING.
この他、SPWN上ではデジタルフラワースタンドの受付も開始しています。
In addition, we're accepting digital flower stands on SPWN.
詳細はSPWNの公演ページをチェックしてね。
Check the SPWN event page for details.
改めまして、チケットの申し込みURLなど詳細は、
Once again, for ticket application URLs and other details,
特設ホームページやホロライブプロダクションイベント総合Twitterをチェックしてください。
please check the special website or the Hololive Production event Twitter account.
そして、ライブといえば、ライブグッズ！
And when you think of a live concert, you think of live merch!
各グッズサイトで今回のライブグッズが発表されております。
The merchandise for this concert has been announced on various sites.
日本のお客様はSPWNの公演ページで、
Customers in Japan can buy them on the SPWN event page,
海外のお客様はGeek Jackさんで買えます。
and overseas customers can buy them from Geek Jack.
なお、応援セット、Tシャツ、アクリルプレートライト、
The Support Set, T-shirt, Acrylic Plate Light,
フェイスタオルは先行発送アイテムになり、
and Face Towel are early shipping items,
日本のお客様はライブ前にゲットできちゃいます！
so customers in Japan can get them before the concert!
応援セットを買ったお客様には、チケットケース＆チケット風ステッカーもプレゼントしちゃいます。
Customers who buy the Support Set will also receive a ticket case and ticket-style sticker.
先行発送アイテムは在庫に限りがあるので、お早めにお買い求めください。
Early shipping items are limited in quantity, so please buy them soon.
ふぅ。ふぅ。
*Deep breaths*
いっぱい一気に台本読んだから疲れちゃったよ。
I'm exhausted from reading so much script all at once.
でもまだまだ行きますよ。
But I'm not done yet.
アクリルスタンド、ビッグ缶バッジ、ロゴラバーキーホルダーは
The Acrylic Stand, Big Can Badge, and Logo Rubber Keychain
受注商品となり、在庫の上限はありません。
are made-to-order, so there's no stock limit.
ライブ後のお届けになりますので、ご注意ください。
Please note they will be delivered after the concert.
えー、このね、グッズたちはですね、もうここになるまでに、
Well, for these goods, until we reached this point,
もうパターンA, B, C, Dからデザイン考えましょう、みたいな感じで、
we were thinking about designs like Pattern A, B, C, D,
たくさん候補案があった中...
and among many candidate ideas...
中から、選ばれたよりすぐりのね、アイテムたちなんですよ。
So these are the carefully selected items.
僕もいっぱい考えたし、あの運営さんとも一緒に、
I thought a lot about it, and discussed with the staff...
どうしようかどうしようかって、考えて決めたものなので、もう、めちゃくちゃ可愛いです。
...over and over to decide on them, so they are incredibly cute!
はい。
Yes.
では、えー、ライブ参戦に必須なアイテム、アクリルプレートライト、Tシャツ、フェイスタオルがセットになりました。
Now then, the essential items for the live: the acrylic plate light, T-shirt, and face towel come as a set.
特典でチケットケースとチケット風ステッカーがついてくるから、絶対ゲットしてね。
It comes with a ticket case and ticket-style sticker as a bonus, so make sure to get yours!
えー、ほいずにゃ〜しんどろーむ、アクリルプレートライト、えー、Tシャツ、フェイスタオルですね、こちら。
Uh, Poisonya Syndrome acrylic plate light, T-shirt, and face towel... right here.
めっちゃ可愛くない？
Aren't they super cute?
フェイスタオルのデザインもめっちゃ迷ったし、Tシャツも、
I also debated a lot about the face towel design, and the T-shirt too...
一匹猫、ここらへんに、黄緑の猫のワンポイントがついてるんだけど、
there's a lime green cat one-point detail right around here.
これをもうちょっと内側にするか、もうちょっと外側にするか、もうめっちゃ迷ったの。
I really struggled with whether to put it a bit more inward or a bit more outward.
そういうね、細かいところまで、いっぱい悩みんで作ったデザインとなっておりますので、
It's a design that I made after agonizing over even those tiny details, so...
よろしくお願いします。
...please look forward to it!
では、次参りましょう。ぽいっ。
Now, let's move on to the next one. Voila!
ほいずにゃ〜しんどろーむグッズ。
Poisonya Syndrome Goods.
えー、こちらは、Tシャツ、アクリルプレートライト、フェイスタオル。
These are the T-shirt, acrylic plate light, and face towel.
えー、こちらはバラで買うこともできます。はい。
These can also be purchased individually. Yes.
なので、まあちょっと全部は買うの難しいかなって人でも、
So, even if it might be difficult to buy the whole set...
こうバラでね、ちょっと欲しいものだけ買うっていうのもできるようになってるんで、よろしくお願いします。
...you can just get the specific items you want, so please consider it!
では、次の画像行きます。ほい。
Alright, next image. Hoi!
えー、こちらはですね、ロゴラバーキーホルダー、BIG缶バッジスタンド、アクリルスタンドとなっております。
Here we have the logo rubber keychain, big can badge stand, and acrylic stand.
可愛いね。
They're cute, right?
もうスタンドも飾ってほしいし、このロゴラバーキーホルダーつけて、
I want you to display the stands, and wear the logo rubber keychain...
いつも、出歩いてほしいし、
...and go out with it all the time.
このBIG缶バッジスタンドは、飾れるようにスタンドになってるから、どこにでも飾れちゃう。
And this big can badge stand is a stand so it can be displayed anywhere.
パソコンの横とかにも置けるし、
You can put it next to your PC...
もう僕のグッズを飾ってる棚がある人とかは、もうそれだけで飾れるようになっています。
...or if you have a shelf for my goods, you can display it right there.
えー、いずれのグッズも、購入の際に、各グッズサイトに書かれている注意事項をチェックしてください。
For all the items, please check the notes written on each merchandise site when purchasing.
そして、今回ライブグッズは現地会場では販売されないので、ぜひグッズサイトをチェックしてみてください。
Also, the live goods will not be sold at the venue this time, so please check the merchandise site!
また、今回特別協賛の株式会社ブシロード様からお知らせがあります。
Additionally, we have an announcement from our special sponsor, Bushiroad Inc.
現地にご来場していただいたお客様へは、入場時に、
To all guests attending the venue, at the entrance...
今回のライブのキービジュアルデザインを使用した、『Rebirth for you』PRカードをプレゼントします。
...we'll present a 'Rebirth for you' PR card featuring the live's key visual!
ぜひ、手に入れてね。
Please make sure to get one!
そして、最後に、どん！
And finally... Bam!
先日発表した、僕の1stアルバムのタイトルは、『ほいずにゃ〜しんどろーむ』になります。
The title of my 1st album, which was announced recently, will be 'Poisonya Syndrome'!
ライブと一緒です。可愛い。
The same as the live. Cute!
ライブとアルバムの名前、別々にしようかなとか考えたんだけど、
I thought about giving the live and the album different names, but...
まあ、よりね、みんなの印象に残ればなということで、同じ名前にさせていただきました。
...I decided on the same name to make it more memorable for everyone.
アルバムジャケットとトラックリストも公開しました。
We've also revealed the album jacket and the tracklist.
ライブのキービジュアルと同じく、アルバムジャケットのイラストは上岡ちろるママ、
Like the live visual, the album jacket illustration is by Chirol Kamioka-mama...
ロゴのデザイン、ロゴとデザインは藤宮藍先生が担当されました。
...and the logo and design are by Ai Fujimiya-sensei.
今までに発表した、『もぐもぐYUMMY!』、『デタバレネコ』、
Including 'Mogu Mogu Yummy!', 'Detabare Neko'...
『毒の王子さま』、『アデュー、サロー』を含む、合計12曲が収録されています。
...'Doku no Oujisama', and 'Adieu, Salow', a total of 12 songs are included.
もうね、全部、この曲、大好きで、
Man, I love all of these songs...
で僕の大好きな人たちにお願いしてるのね。
...and I asked some of my favorite people to work on them.
だから、早くみんなに聴いてほしいな。
So, I really want you all to hear them soon!
マジで早く聴いてほしい。まあ1から12番まで全部説明するとたぶん10時ぐらいになっちゃうんで、
Seriously, I want you to hear them. Explaining all 12 songs would take until 10 PM,
まあここのページね、スクショなりなんなりして、ちょっと見返してもらえればなと思います。
so I hope you'll take a screenshot of this page and look back at it.
では、アルバムのハッシュタグは #ほいずにゃーしんどろーむ です。
Now, the hashtag for the album is #PoisonyaSyndrome.
おかゆソロライブと合わせて、どんどんツイートしていっちゃってください。
Please keep tweeting along with the Okayu solo live.
改めて、言い切った！情報盛りだくさんだったね、みんな。
Once again, I've said it all! There was so much info, everyone.
嬉しい、嬉しい。僕はね、僕はもう、すごく嬉しいし、
I'm happy, so happy. As for me, I'm just so happy, and...
今日という日に、みんなにね、発表できたのがすごく嬉しい。
...I'm so glad I could announce this to everyone today.
ずっとずっと言いたかった。7月24日が本当に待ち遠しかったよ、みんな。
I've been wanting to say this forever. July 24th was a long time coming.
おめでとありがとね、見えてるよ。ありがとう、ありがとう。
Thanks for the congrats, I see them! Thank you, thank you!
えーっと、ソロライブの開催、キービジュアルやロゴの発表、現地や配信チケットや、グッズ情報、
The solo live, key visual and logo reveal, venue and streaming tickets, merchandise...
現地の来場者特典やアルバム情報、などなど。ライブの情報に関しては、直接ホームページもオープンしています。
...venue bonus and album info, etc. The official website for the live is now open.
公演の注意事項などもこちらにアップされているので、ぜひ見てね。
Precautions for the performance are also uploaded there, so please check it.
ライブ開催まで、約2ヶ月。
There are about two months until the live.
僕もみんなと会えるのが待ち遠しいです！
I also can't wait to see everyone!
これからもどんどんビッグニュースが発表される予定なので、
More and more big news is scheduled to be announced from now on,
楽しみに待っててね！
so please look forward to it!
以上、猫又おかゆでした！
That's all from Nekomata Okayu!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
香りまとわせ　思うがままに
Wrapped in scent, just as I please
この身体のどこかに　生まれ持っていたなら
If I was born with it somewhere in this body
何ものにも食せぬ　毒毒毒
Something that can't be eaten by anything, poison poison poison
うたうような甘さと　嗅ぎ回られもしようが
With a singing sweetness, even if I'm sniffed around
喉から手が出るほど　毒毒毒
So much that I'm dying for it, poison poison poison
気高く立って　じっとしていられるのなら
If you can stand tall and stay still
のぞむかい
do you want it?
Swallow, swallow, その唇で
Swallow, swallow, with those lips
猫又おかゆ 初のワンマンライブ 開催決定！
Nekomata Okayu's first solo live concert confirmed!
深く患った病を　求めついばむ
Seeking and pecking at a deeply-seated illness
2022.9.30(Fri) TACHIKAWA STAGE GARDEN
September 30, 2022 (Fri) at Tachikawa Stage Garden
願うまま　今をこなせればと
Hoping to just make it through the now
現地チケット1次先行(抽選)受付開始！
In-person ticket 1st lottery pre-sale begins!
乱れかかる喉を鳴らす
Purring with a disheveled throat
詳細は特設HPをチェック
Check the special website for details
何食わぬ顔さえ
Even with a nonchalant face
こっそり牙を宿していたい
I want to keep my fangs hidden
かじりつき　平らげて
Bite into it, eat it all up
猫又おかゆ 1stアルバム「ぽいずにゃ〜しんどろーむ」
Nekomata Okayu 1st Album "Poisonya Syndrome"
2022.9.6 Release
Released on September 6, 2022
重大発表!?
Major announcement!?